<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contribute on Magic Modules</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/</link><description>Recent content in Contribute on Magic Modules</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Write release notes</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/release-notes/</guid><description>Write release notes # This guide explains best practices for composing accurate, end-user focused release notes for Magic Modules pull requests.
Every pull request must have at least one release note block in the opening comment. Release note blocks have the following format:
```release-note:TYPE CONTENT ``` Replace TYPE with the correct release note type, and CONTENT with a release note written according to the guidelines in the following sections.</description></item><item><title>Review a PR</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/review-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/review-pr/</guid><description>Review a PR # This page provides guidelines for reviewing Magic Modules pull requests
Read the PR description to understand the context and ensure the PR either is linked to a GitHub issue or an internal bug if not, check the issue tracker to see whether the feature has already been requested and add the issues in the description, if any. establishes clear context itself via title or description. If the PR adds any new resource, ensure that the resource does not already exists in the GA provider or beta provider Read through all the changes in the PR, generated code in the downstreams and the API documentation to ensure that: the resource schema added in the PR matches the API structure.</description></item></channel></rss>