<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contribute on Magic Modules</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/</link><description>Recent content in Contribute on Magic Modules</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a pull request</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/create-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/create-pr/</guid><description>Create a pull request (PR) # Requirements # Make sure your branch contains a single self-contained change. For example: If you are adding multiple resources to the provider, only put one resource in each PR - even if the product requires all resources to be present before it can be meaningfully used. If you are adding a few fields and also fixing a bug, create one PR for adding the new fields and a separate PR for the bugs.</description></item><item><title>Write release notes</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/release-notes/</guid><description>Write release notes # This guide explains best practices for composing accurate, end-user focused release notes for Magic Modules pull requests.
Every pull request must have at least one release note block in the opening comment. Release note blocks have the following format:
```release-note:TYPE CONTENT ``` Replace TYPE with the correct release note type, and CONTENT with a release note written according to the guidelines in the following sections.</description></item><item><title>Review a pull request</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/review-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/contribute/review-pr/</guid><description>Review a pull request # This page provides guidelines for reviewing a Magic Modules pull request (PR).
Read the PR description to understand the context and ensure the PR either is linked to a GitHub issue or an internal bug if not, check the issue tracker to see whether the feature has already been requested and add the issues in the description, if any. establishes clear context itself via title or description.</description></item></channel></rss>