<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get started on Magic Modules</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/</link><description>Recent content in Get started on Magic Modules</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generate the providers</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/generate-providers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/generate-providers/</guid><description>Generate google and google-beta providers # This quickstart guides you through setting up your development environment, making a change to magic-modules, generating provider changes to the google and google-beta Terraform providers, and running tests related to the change.
Before you begin # Install the gcloud CLI. In the Google Cloud console, on the project selector page, select or create a Google Cloud project. Note: If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a project to use for testing changes to the Terraform providers, create a project instead of selecting an existing poject.</description></item><item><title>How Magic Modules works</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/how-magic-modules-works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/how-magic-modules-works/</guid><description>How Magic Modules works # Magic Modules can be thought of as a source of truth for how to map a GCP API resource representation to a Terraform resource (or datasource) representation. Magic Modules uses that mapping (and additional handwritten code where necessary) to generate &amp;ldquo;downstream&amp;rdquo; repositories - in particular, the Terraform providers for Google Cloud: google (or TPG) and google-beta (or TPGB).
Generation of the downstream repositories happens for every new commit in a PR (to a temporary branch owned by the modular-magician robot user) and on every merge into the main branch (to the main branch of downstreams).</description></item><item><title>Contribution process</title><link>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/contribution-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://googlecloudplatform.github.io/magic-modules/get-started/contribution-process/</guid><description>Contribution process # Before you begin # Familiarize yourself with GitHub flow Fork the Magic Modules repository into your GitHub account Set up your development environment Check whether the feature you want to work on has already been requested in the issue tracker. If there&amp;rsquo;s an issue and it already has a dedicated assignee, this indicates that someone might have already started to work on a solution. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to work on the issue.</description></item></channel></rss>